nationalprostaff.com 2019-04-28

# NPS Fishing - Fishing Social Network

## NPS Fishing Privacy Policy

#### 1\. Introduction

At National ProStaff Inc. (NPS), we want to give you the best possible experience. To do this we need to collect information from you to provide you with quality, relevant content and product recommendations. That said, your privacy and the security of your personal data is very important to us. Here, we will transparently explain how and why we collect, store, and use your personal data, and outline the controls you have to choose how that data is shared. 

That is our objective, and this Privacy Policy (“Policy”) will explain exactly what we mean in further detail below.

#### 2\. About this Policy

This Policy sets out the essential details relating to your personal data relationship with NPS. The Policy applies to all NPS services and any associated services. The terms governing your use NPS are defined in our Terms and Conditions.

From time to time, we may offer additional services. If the introduction of these new or additional services results in any change to the way we collect or process your personal data we will provide you with more information and additional terms or policies. Unless stated otherwise when we introduce these new or additional services, they will be subject to this Policy.

The aim of this Policy is to:

  1. Ensure that you understand what personal data we collect about you, the reasons why we collect and use it, and who we share it with;
  2. Explain the way we use the personal data that you share with us in order to give you a great experience when you are using NPS; and
  3. Explain your rights and choices in relation to the personal data we collect and process about you and how we will protect your privacy.

We hope this helps you to understand our privacy commitments to you. For further clarification of the terms used in this Policy please visit our Privacy FAQ. For information on how to contact us if you ever have any questions or concerns, then please see the ‘How to Contact Us’ section below Alternatively, if you do not agree with the content of this Policy, then please remember it is your choice whether you want to use the National Prostaff Service.

#### 3\. Your rights and your preferences: Giving you choice and control

You may be aware that a new European Union law, called the General Data Protection Regulation or "GDPR" gives certain rights to individuals in relation to their personal data. As available and except as limited under applicable law, the rights afforded to individuals are:

  * Right of Access - the right to be informed of and request access your personal data
  * Right to Rectification - the right to request that we amend or update your personal data where it is inaccurate or incomplete;
  * Right to Erasure - the right to request that we delete your personal data;
  * Right to Restrict - the right to request that we temporarily or permanently stop processing all or some of your personal data;
  * Right to Object - 
    * the right, at any time, to object to us processing your personal data on grounds relating to your particular situation;
    * the right to object to your personal data being processed for direct marketing purposes;
  * Right to Data Portability - the right to request a copy of your personal data in electronic format and the right to transmit that personal data for use in another party’s service; and
  * Right not to be subject to Automated Decision-making - the right to not be subject to a decision based solely on automated decision making, including profiling, where the decision would have a legal effect on you or produce a similarly significant effect.

In order to enable you to exercise these rights with ease and to record your preferences in relation to how NPS uses your personal data, we provide you with access to the following settings via submission of a written request to NPS.

  * **Notification Settings** \- allows you to choose which communications you receive from National Prostaff, and set your sharing preferences.

If we send you electronic marketing messages based on your consent or as otherwise permitted by applicable law, you may, at any time, respectively withdraw such consent or declare your objection (“opt-out”) at no cost. The electronic marketing messages you receive from NPS (e.g. those sent via email) also will include an opt-out mechanism within the message itself (e.g. an unsubscribe link in the emails we send to you).

You can find out more about the GDPR rights described above on the [GDPR Website](https://www.eugdpr.org/). If you have any questions about your privacy, your rights, or how to exercise them, please contact our Data Protection Officer using the ‘Contact Us’ form . We will respond to your request within a reasonable period of time upon verification of your identity. If you are unhappy with the way we are using your personal data you can also contact and are free to lodge a complaint with your local Data Protection Authority.

#### 4\. How do we collect your personal data?

We collect your personal data in the following ways:

  1. _When you sign up for the National Prostaff Service_ \- when you sign up to the National Prostaff Service, we collect certain personal data so you can use the National Prostaff Service such as your email address, birth date, gender, and country.
  2. _Through your use of the National Prostaff Service_ \- Through your use of NPS - when you use NPS, we collect personal data about your use of NPS Service, such as the locations of your posts, the gear and fish species that you tag, and the products you purchase, and the frequency of your visits.
  3. _Personal data collected that enables us to provide you with additional features/functionality_ \- from time to time, you also may also provide us with additional personal data or give us your permission to collect additional personal data e.g. to provide you with more features or functionality. We will not collect photos, precise mobile device location, or contacts from your device without your prior consent. You always will have the option to change your mind and withdraw your consent at any time.
  4. _From third parties_ \- we will receive personal data about you and your activity from third parties, including advertisers and partners we work with in order to provide you with the National Prostaff Service (please see ‘Sharing your personal data’ section below). We will use this personal data either where you have provided your consent to the third party or to National Prostaff to that data sharing taking place or where National Prostaff has a legitimate interest to use the personal data in order to provide you with the service.

We use anonymised and aggregated information for purposes that include testing our IT systems, research, data analysis, creating marketing and promotion models, improving NPS, and developing new features.

#### 5.What personal data do we collect from you?

Personal information is any information that can identify or get in contact with someone such as, but not limited to, an email address, full name, date of birth, address, phone number, photos, videos, blogs, reviews, applications, comments, updates, personal websites (URL’S), reports, and other information contributed. Other information is any information that is not personal information that is gathered by NationalProstaff.com. This includes, but is not limited to, user navigation, statistics, page views, length of visit, browser used, operating system used, and search engine used. IP Address is the number your device is assigned to that our server uses to send your device information. Every time you visit NationalProstaff.com we collect information that you provide by either using our website, using services, posting content, exchanging data and registering on NationalProstaff.com

We have set out in the tables below the categories of personal data we collect and use about you:

**_Personal data collected when you sign up for the National Prostaff Service_**

Categories of personal data | Description of category  
---|---  
**Account Registration Data** | 

This is the personal data that is provided by you or collected by us to enable you to sign up for and use the National Prostaff Service. This includes your email address, birth date, gender, postal code, and country.

Some of the personal data we will ask you to provide is required in order to create your account. You also have the option to provide us with some additional personal data in order to make your account more personalized.

The exact personal data we will collect depends on the type of National Prostaff Service plan you sign up for and whether or not you use a Third Party Service (as defined in the Terms and Conditions of Use, such as Facebook) to sign up and use the National Prostaff Service. If you use a Third Party Service to create an account, we will receive personal data via that Third Party Service but only when you have consented to that Third Party Service sharing your personal data with us.  
  
**_Personal data collected through your use of the National Prostaff Service_**

Categories of personal data | Description of category  
---|---  
**Service Usage Data** | 

This is the personal data that is collected about you when you are using the National Prostaff Service - this may include:

  * Information about your type of National Prostaff Service plan.
  * Information about your interactions with the National Prostaff Service which includes the date and time of any requests you make, posts you have viewed or created, video content you’ve watched, and your interactions with other National Prostaff users. This also may also include details of your use of Third Party Applications and advertising you receive.
  * User Content (as defined in the Terms and Conditions of Use) you post to National Prostaff including messages you send and/or receive via National Prostaff and your interactions with the National Prostaff Customer Service team.
  * Technical Data which may include URL information, cookie data, your IP address, the types of devices you are using to access or connect to the National Prostaff Service, unique device IDs, device attributes, network connection type (e.g. WiFi, 3G, LTE, Bluetooth) and provider, network and device performance, browser type, language, information enabling digital rights management, operating system, and National Prostaff application version. Further details about the technical data that is processed by us can be found in our Cookies Policy.
  * Motion-generated or orientation-generated mobile sensor data (e.g. accelerometer or gyroscope) required for the purposes of providing specific features of the National Prostaff Service to you.

**_Personal data collected with your permission that enables us to provide you with additional features/functionality_**

Categories of personal data | Description of category  
---|---  
**Voluntary Mobile Data** | 

In addition to the mobile data we collect to provide you with the National Prostaff Service (outlined above), you also have the option to give us your consent to collect additional personal data from your mobile device to provide you with features/functionality that will enhance your National Prostaff Service experience. 

We will not access any of the personal data listed below without first obtaining your consent:

  * Your photos - If you give us permission to access your photos or camera, we will only access images that you specifically choose to share with us and metadata related to those images, such as the type of file and the size of the image. We will never scan or import your photo library or camera roll;
  * Your precise mobile device location - If you give us permission to access your precise location, this enables us to access your GPS or Bluetooth to provide location-aware functionality in the National Prostaff Service. Please note that this does not include your IP address. We use your IP address to determine non-precise location, for example, what country you are in to comply with our licensing agreements;
  * Your voice data - If you give us permission, this enables us to access the voice commands captured via your device microphone, to enable you to interact with the National Prostaff Service with your voice. Please note you will always have the ability to turn off the microphone feature; and,
  * Your contacts - If you give us permission to access your contacts, this enables us to access individual contacts stored on your device to help you find friends who use National Prostaff.

**Payment Data** | 

We may collect such personal data if you sign up for a Trial or purchase any of our Paid Subscriptions (as defined in the Terms and Conditions of Use) or make other purchases through the National Prostaff Service. The exact personal data collected will vary depending on the payment method (e.g. direct via your mobile phone carrier or by invoice) but will include information such as:

  * Name;
  * Date of birth;
  * Credit or debit card type, expiration date, and certain digits of your card number;
  * Postal code;
  * Mobile phone number; and
  * Details of your transaction history.

**Contests, Surveys and Sweepstakes Data** | 

This personal data is used to allow you to sign up and participate in these types of promotions. The exact personal data collected will vary depending on the promotion. If you choose to apply to any company for a sponsorship opportunity or participate in any contest, your information may be required to be disclosed in the form of a list of winners by Law. We may at any time introduce and offer contest and sponsorship opportunities. This may require that you disclose personal information in order to participate. If it is disclosed on the contest or promotions page in the rules, third parties may gather information you submit to participate/register for the promotion. In such a case, we have no control over the third party and how they chose to use that information and that third party would not be subject to this Privacy Policy.  
  
**Marketing Data** | 

This personal data is used to enable National Prostaff and our partners / service providers to send you marketing communications either:

  * Via email;
  * Whilst using the National Prostaff Service; and/or
  * Direct from the third party.

You can find out more about the personal data collected and the controls you have in relation to the marketing communications you receive via the Privacy FAQ on www.nationalprostaff.com.  
  
#### 6\. What do we use your personal data for?

When you use or interact with the National Prostaff Service, we use a variety of technologies to process the personal data we collect about you for various reasons. We have set out in the table below the reasons why we process your personal data, the associated legal bases we rely upon to legally permit us to process your personal data, and the categories of personal data (identified in the section ‘What personal data do we collect from you?’) used for these purposes:

Description of why National Prostaff processes your personal data (‘processing purpose’) | Legal Basis for the processing purpose | Categories of personal data used by National Prostaff for the processing purpose  
---|---|---  
To provide, personalize, and improve your experience with the National Prostaff Service and other services and products provided by National Prostaff, for example by providing customized, personalized, or localized content, recommendations, features, and advertising on or outside of the National Prostaff Service (including for third party products and services). | 

  * Performance of a Contract
  * Legitimate Interest

| 

  * Account Registration Data
  * Service Usage Data

To understand how you access and use the National Prostaff Service to ensure technical functionality of the National Prostaff Service, develop new products and services, and analyze your use of the National Prostaff Service, including your interaction with applications, advertising, products, and services that are made available, linked to, or offered through the National Prostaff Service. | 

  * Performance of a Contract
  * Legitimate Interest

| 

  * Account Registration Data
  * Service Usage Data

To communicate with you for National Prostaff Service-related purposes. | 

  * Performance of a Contract
  * Legitimate Interest

| 

  * Account Registration Data
  * Service Usage Data

To process your payment to prevent or detect fraud including fraudulent payments and fraudulent use of the National Prostaff Service. | 

  * Performance of a Contract
  * Compliance with legal obligations
  * Legitimate Interest

| 

  * Payment Data

To communicate with you, either directly or through one of our partners, for:

  * marketing,
  * research,
  * participation in contests, surveys and sweepstakes,
  * promotional purposes,

via emails, notifications, or other messages, consistent with any permissions you may have communicated to us (e.g., through your Account Settings page).

| 

  * Consent
  * Legitimate Interest

| 

  * Contests, Surveys and Sweepstakes Data
  * Marketing Data

To provide you with features, information, advertising, or other content which is based on your specific location. | 

  * Consent

| 

  * Voluntary Mobile Data

#### 7\. Sharing your personal data

We have set out the categories of recipients of the personal data collected or generated through your use of the National Prostaff Service.

**_Publicly available information_**

The following personal data will always be publicly available on the National Prostaff Service: your name and/or username, profile picture, who you follow and who follows you on the National Prostaff Service, your sponsorships, posts, tagged gear and comments..

**_Personal data you may choose to share_**

The following personal data will only be shared with the categories of recipients outlined in the table below if:

  * you choose to make use of a specific National Prostaff Service feature where sharing of particular personal data is required for the proper use of the National Prostaff Service feature; or
  * you grant us your permission to share the personal data, e.g. by selecting the appropriate setting in the National Prostaff Service.

NationalProstaff.com allows you to manage your profile and limit the information that appears on your profile as well as allowing you to control the amount of information you receive from us. You have the ability to remove and delete any of your personal content. We also reserve the right if we feel it’s necessary to remove posts, comments, or other content that originates from you

Categories of Recipients | Reason for sharing  
---|---  
**Third Party Applications you connect to your National Prostaff Account** | 

If you connect your National Prostaff account to a Third Party Application, such as, for example, social media, audio, television, or automotive platforms, National Prostaff may share your Service Usage Data so you can connect to your National Prostaff account.  
  
**Third Party Applications you use to log into National Prostaff** | 

If you log into a Third Party Application using your National Prostaff account credentials, then that Third Party Application may have access to certain Service Usage Data such as your saved content and activity.

You will receive a notification before connecting to the Third Party Application to let you know what personal data will be shared / accessible to that Third Party Application.  
  
**Your NPS Fishing Followers** | 

There also may be times when you want us to share certain Service Usage Data, specifically information about your use of National Prostaff, with other National Prostaff users known as ‘Your National Prostaff Followers’.  
  
Learn more about how to manage notifications, your publicly available information, and what you share with others in the ‘Your rights and your preferences: Giving you choice and control’ section of this Policy and on the Privacy Center.

**_Information we may share_**

Categories of Recipients | Reason for sharing  
---|---  
**Service Providers and Others** | We use technical service providers which may operate the technical infrastructure that we need to provide the National Prostaff Service, in particular providers which host, store, manage, and maintain the National Prostaff application, its content and the data we process.  
We use technical service providers to help us communicate with you.  
We use marketing and advertising partners to show you more tailored content, or to help us understand your use of the National Prostaff Service, to provide you with a better service. We also may also share personal data with certain marketing and advertising partners to send you promotional communications about National Prostaff.   
**National Prostaff Partners** | 

If you access the National Prostaff Service through an offer that you received or purchased from a third party such as your mobile network operator, we share personal data with that third party about your use of the National Prostaff Service, such as whether and to what extent you have used the offer, activated a National Prostaff account, or actively used the National Prostaff Service.  
Depending on how you sign up for the National Prostaff Service (e.g. through a third party service or a mobile provider), we share your National Prostaff username or other Account Registration Data as necessary to enable your account.  
We may also share your personal data in a pseudonymised format with marketing partners who help us with promotional efforts, and with advertisers that allow us to offer a free service.  
  
**Academic Researchers** | We will share your personal data for activities such as statistical analysis and academic study, but only in a pseudonymised format.  
**Other National Prostaff Group Companies** | We will share your personal data with other National Prostaff Group companies to carry out our daily business operations and to enable us to maintain and provide the National Prostaff Service to you.  
**Law Enforcement and Data Protection Authorities** | 

We will share your personal data when we in good faith believe it is necessary for us to do so in order to comply with a legal obligation under applicable law, or respond to valid legal process, such as a search warrant, a court order, or a subpoena.

We also will also share your personal data where we, in good faith, believe that it is necessary for the purpose of our own, or a third party’s legitimate interest relating to national security, law enforcement, litigation, criminal investigation, protecting the safety of any person, or to prevent death or imminent bodily harm, provided that we deem that such interest is not overridden by your interests or fundamental rights and freedoms requiring the protection of your personal data.

Finally we may share your personal information if we feel you are a threat to our services, service providers, features, functionality, rights, property, other unaffiliated parties, members, pro-staff, premium members, clients, employees, or the and safety of National Prostaff.  
  
**Asset Protection/Purchase** | 

We will share your personal data if we believe it is necessary to protect our business, its assets, defend our interests, exercise our legal rights, and/or to comply with legal and regulatory obligations.

Furthermore, we may sharre your personal data in the possible event of bankruptcy, merger, acquisition, joint venture, consolidation, transfer of control, fundamental corporate change(s) or any other possible business combination involving National Prostaff.  
  
#### 8\. Data Retention and Deletion

We keep your personal data only as long as necessary to provide you with the National Prostaff Service and for legitimate and essential business purposes, such as maintaining the performance of the National Prostaff Service, making data-driven business decisions about new features and offerings, complying with our legal obligations, and resolving disputes. We keep some of your personal data for as long as you are a user of the National Prostaff Service. For example, we keep your posts, followers list, comments, sponsorships and account information.

If you request, we will delete or anonymise your personal data so that it no longer identifies you, unless, we are legally allowed or required to maintain certain personal data, including situations such as the following:

  * If there is an unresolved issue relating to your account, such as an outstanding credit on your account or an unresolved claim or dispute we will retain the necessary personal data until the issue is resolved;
  * Where we are required to retain the personal data for our legal, tax, audit, and accounting obligations, we will retain the necessary personal data for the period required by applicable law; and/or,
  * Where necessary for our legitimate business interests such as fraud prevention or to maintain the security of our users.

#### 9\. Links

We may display advertisements from third parties and other content that links to third-party websites. We cannot control or be held responsible for third parties’ privacy practices and content. If you click on a third-party advertisement or link, please understand that you are leaving the National Prostaff Service and any personal data you provide will not be covered by this Policy. Please read their privacy policies to find out how they collect and process your personal data.

#### 10\. Children

The National Prostaff Service is not directed to children under the age of 13 years. If you are between the age of 13 and 17 or under the legal age/age of majority where you reside (stricter age limits may apply under local law), before using NationalProstaff.com kindly review the Agreement with your parent or guardian. Please see our Terms and Conditions of Use for further details.

We do not knowingly collect personal data from children under 13 years or under the applicable age limit (the “Age Limit”). If you are under the Age Limit, please do not use the National Prostaff Service, and do not provide any personal data to us.

Until you reach the legal age or age of majority where you reside, you confirm that you have full parental consent for your use of NationalProstaff.com and that you and your parent have carefully read and agreed to the Privacy Policy and Terms of Use. You confirm that your parent or guardian have full access at all times to your username, email address, and password. You also acknowledge that your parent or guardian may choose to make changes or terminate your account and access to NationalProstaff.com and that we may do so at their request for any reason without notice, responsibility and at any time.

If you are a parent of a child under the Age Limit and become aware that your child has provided personal data to National Prostaff, please contact us using the ‘Contact Us’ form on the Privacy Center, and you may request exercise of your applicable rights detailed in the ‘Your rights and your preferences: Giving you choice and control’ section of this Policy.

If we learn that we have collected the personal data of a child under the age of 13 years (and do not have verified parental/guardian consent), we will immediately take reasonable steps to delete the personal data. This may require us to delete the National Prostaff account for that child.

By using NationalProstaff.com you confirm that you are at least 13 years of age and meet all requirements to use this website. If you are under the age of 13 or do not meet all requirements of eligibility, immediately stop use of NationalProstaff.com and do not submit any personal information about yourself.

#### 11\. Laws surrounding National Prostaff

NationalProstaff.com was established in Canada which means that you are accessing a networking site that is governed by the laws of Canada. NationalProstaff.com is in no way governed by the laws of other nations. Please be aware that any personal information you provide to us as a result of your membership or use of NationalProstaff.com will be collected in Canada and/or transferred, to Canada. By using NationalProstaff.com and/or providing us with your personal information or other information you (a) consent to transfer, processing and/or storage of any personal information and other information you provide; (b) understand and agree to Canadian Standards and Laws; (c) understand that your information will be collected, transferred to, dealt with or stored in accordance with our Privacy Policy and current legislation. By using the website you are agreeing to waive any claims that may arise as a result of laws originating in other countries or jurisdictions.

#### 12\. Security

National Prostaff strives to maintain reasonable standards of security and confidentiality of information. This is achieved through the use of firewall protection and the information access limitations our employees are subject to. Only fully authorized individuals have access to certain information. If we believe or find any individual is in violation of our standards and security, this individual will be subject to disciplinary measures at our discretion. It is our request that any of our affiliated third parties follow the same policy. No data transmitted over the internet is 100% secure and for any internet site, there exists a real possibility that third parties could unlawfully intercept and or gain access to data transmissions and private communications. For this reason, we cannot warrant or guarantee any security of the information we receive and are not responsible for any theft, destruction, misuse, or inadvertent disclosure of any information.

#### 13\. Use of Cookies

Cookies are designed to increase the "made for you” experience of NationalProstaff.com in order to make the user experience more enjoyable. These cookies are little data files that are inserted in your device(s) when you access any community site. These cookies can be used for multiple purposes which include, but are not limited to, tracking usage of services or features, allowing personalization of features and your experiences, measuring clicks and visits, determining how you use our site and when, limiting repetitive data input, making navigation easier, verifying certain information, identifying your web browser, and for screening processes. Cookies are not used to identify age or ensure parental consent is granted, and therefore we cannot guarantee the age of visitors. As soon as you logout and/or close your internet browser, these cookies expire and are no longer effective. You can set your internet browser or antivirus to reject cookies if you wish to do so and would like to disallow them. Please be aware that by disallowing the use of cookies, certain aspects, features and pages may not function as intended and/or may hinder your user experience.

#### 14\. Advertising and content providers

When you visit company profiles and their team of Prostaff profiles, these companies or individuals may offer and post various forms of advertisements. These third parties will be offered tracking technologies by National Prostaff to determine the effectiveness of their advertising efforts and their presence on the website. They will use this information to better tailor their advertising initiatives and to attempt to enhance your through both their corporate team page and Prostaff profile pages as well as the combined information they share on our website. These tracking technologies will allow them to count views of their content and the approximate physical location of individuals that view their content. We do not have access or control over their tracking capabilities, and in no way have access to the information they have collected using these technologies. These tracking technologies and information collected are therefore subject to these third parties’ privacy policies. We highly recommend that if you have any questions surrounding their privacy policies that you contact these individuals and third party companies directly.

#### 15\. Social networking sites

You have the ability to access and/or interact with the features and services of NationalProstaff.com from various social networking sites such as, but not limited to, Facebook, Instagram, and Twitter. Under these circumstances, your information could be shared with these social networking sites and they may also share and transfer data to us. If you would like to educate yourself about the social networking sites, and the “share this” functionality NationalProstaff.com utilizes and interacts with, we suggest you visit these sites directly and review their Terms and Conditions and Privacy Policy on a regular basis. Since we have no control over the social networking sites we connect with, if you choose to share your information with these social networking sites, your information will be treated and governed by their Policies. Any information we gather from interaction and data sharing with these sites will be governed by this Privacy Policy. Please be aware that the social networking sites we connect with may choose to utilize cookies or other similar types of files. These social networking sites may have different rules than NationalProstaff.com. These social networking sites may provide us with information from your accounts with them that we can use to enhance your experience on NationalProstaff.com. This information will create a more personalized experience for you which is better tailored to you. You also have the ability to share your experience on NationalProstaff.com on sites such as Facebook. You have the ability to control and limit the amount of information that is transmitted to these sites and your friends by adjusting your personal settings on the sites you share on. Please ensure your personal settings with these sites are adjusted to your liking.

#### 16\. How to contact us

Thank you for reading our Privacy Policy. If you have any questions about this Policy, please contact our Data Protection Officer by using the ‘Contact Us’ form or by writing to us at the following address:

[[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#fc9e99889d8c8e939b8e9d91bc929d889593929d908c8e938f889d9a9ad29f9391c38f899e96999f88c1ac8e958a9d9f85dcac9390959f85dcad89998f889593928f)

National Prostaff Inc  
21 Simcoe St S  
Oshawa, ON, L1H 4G1  
Canada 

We hope you enjoy NPS Fishing!  
© National Prostaff Inc.
